Nicolas de la Torre

Buenos Aires, Argentina | nicodelatorre7@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ndelatorre- | github.com/nicodelatorre7

Авоит

Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in software development, specializing in frontend, backend, and smart contract technologies. Committed to implementing efficient and scalable solutions, backed by a strong understanding of agile development and a continuous improvement mindset.

EDUCATION

Instituto Tecnologico de Buenos Aires (ITBA)

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Feb. 2017 - Jul. 2020

Jul. 2020 - Dec. 2022

Instituto Tecnologico de Buenos Aires (ITBA)

Master's degree in Software Engineering (MEng)

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Thesis: Mobile app/game to teach sign language with an animated character, focused on children.
- Related courses: Cryptography, Blockchain, Artificial Intelligence, Virtual Reality, Cloud Computing.

EXPERIENCE

Semi Senior Software Engineer

June 2024 - Present

Remote

- Think and Dev

 Develop ERC20, ERC721, and ERC1155 Smart Contracts. And Smart Contracts testing with Hardhat.
 - Design, develop, and maintain the web application using React, Typescript, Node.js, Redis, and PostgreSQL.
 - Design and implement CI/CD pipelines, streamlining deployment processes and improving code reliability.
 - Leveraged Knowledge: Solidity, TypeScript, HardHat, Web3 Libraries (web3.js and ethers.js), Blockchain, Node.js, Next.js, React, Typescript, Library development, CI/CD.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Dec. 2021 – May 2024

Ensuro Remote

- Development of applications in the Web3 environment, encompassing the creation of Smart Contracts.
- Development and maintenance of the frontend and backend.
- Leveraged Knowledge: Solidity, React, TypeScript, Web3 Libraries (web3.js and ethers.js), Express.js, HardHat, Jest, Blockchain, DeFi, GCP, CI/CD, Python (Django).

Full Stack Software Engineer

Feb. 2021 - Dec. 2021

AFIP

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Design, development, and deployment of WebApps.
- Expertise in comprehensive maintenance of the Frontend, Backend, and databases. Proficient in handling technologies such as Java, Vue.js, JavaScript, Nodejs, and Oracle DB.

Projects

Ensenias | C#, Unity, Figma, Blender

July 2021 – July 2022

- Design the application in Figma. Develop a mobile application/game to teach sign language.
- Sign-by-sign creation of each of the letters of the alphabet, numbers, common expressions, and colors.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Solidity, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, C/C++, SQL (Postgres), CSS/SCSS, HTML.

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Django, Vue.js, Next.js, Express.js, Springboot, AWS Services.

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, CI/CD (GitHub Actions), VS Code, IntelliJ.

Testing Tools: HardHat, Jest, Mocha, Chai, Cypress.

Technologies: Web3, Blockchain, Cryptography, Google Cloud, AWS, Docker.

Web3 Libraries: HardHat, Foundry, web3.js, ethers.js.

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Native

English

Proficient/Fluent proficiency in English.